Daniel González-Suárez

Marine Biologist || Coastal Oceanographer

Linked in

ORCID

GitHub

Marine biologist experienced in the technology industry as a data analyst. Deeply passionate about studying early development of marine invertebrates and competent on rearing invertebrates for environmental-stress experiments. Knowledgeable in data analysis and visualization with programming languages like R and python, as well as with guerying databases with SQL.

Academic Degrees

Personal Info

MSc in Coastal Oceanography 2019-2021

Universidad Autónoma de Baja California

Baja California, México

https://danielgs14.github.io

2017-2019 BSc Marine and Freshwater

Resources Management

danielgs14@gmail.com San José, Costa Rica

Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica (UNA)

April 30th, 1992

2012-2016

BSc in Marine Biology

+50683777802

Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica (UNA)

Work Experience

Hakkoda Analytics Engineer I 2021-2022

Worked with database management using SQL, python and R. Developed protocols for exploratory data analysis and designed dashboards with Sigma, a Business Intelligence tool

INCAPESM, UABC

2021

Research and Training in Production and Growth of Marine Cultures

Worked as laboratory technician, supporting experiments with early development of the Pacific oyster Crassostrea gigas. Classified the embroynic and larval stages and assisted in respirometries for larvae. Performed statistical data analysis and created visualizations for final reports of experiments.

EcoDel. IIO

2019-2021

Ecology and Developmental Biology Laboratory, Institute of Oceanologic Research

Laboratory maintenance, experiment execution and report elaboration. Provided experimental design and statistical guidance for postgraduate students.

CIMAR, UCR

2016-2018

Laboratory assistant (Ad honorem)

Assistant to various researchers for projects about echinoderm research, ocean acidification, seagrass ecology, deep-see idenfitication and database management.

Daniel González-Suárez

Marine Biologist || Coastal Oceanographer

Linked in ORCID GitHub

Research

Daniel González-Suárez & José Carlos Hernández (2022)

Early developmental stages of the sea urchin *Sphaerechinus granularis* (Lamarck, 1816) (Echinoidea: Toxopneustidae).

Marine Biology Research, 18:3-4, 266-277, DOI: 10.1080/17451000.2022.2093375

Congresses

San José, Costa Rica

3311g13333	
17th International Echinoderm Conference	2024
Early development of the sea urchin <i>Arbacia stellata</i> exposed to a thermal range in its northern distribution limit	
V Latin American Echinoderm Congress	2022
Early developmental stages of the sea urchin Sphaerechinus granularis	
III Marine Sciences Scientific Congress	2016
Effectivity of Marine Protected Areas in Costa Rica	
Courses & Workshops	
Exploratory Data Analysis in R	2020
Universidad Autónoma de Baja California (UABC) Baja California, México	
<u>Larval Biology of Marine Invertebrates</u>	2019
Friday Harbor Laboratories, University of Washinton Washington, USA	
Effects of dissolved oxygen stress on larval <i>Haminoea vesicula</i> survivorship and growth Selection of vertical zones in low oxygen water columns by larval <i>Dendraster excentricus</i>	
Systematics, Taxonomy and Ecology of Echinoderms	2019
Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) Yucatán, México	
Administration of Marine Biogeographical Data	2018
INVEMAR & OceanTeacher - Global Academy Santa Marta, Colombia	
Python Programming Academic Workshop	2018
Nationa Center for High Technology (CeNAT)	